<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>https://www.colinspear.com/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.colinspear.com/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2022-03-21</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-21/</guid>
      <description>Articles   Nadia Eghbal&amp;rsquo;s new work sounds really interesting. Hannah and I have been talking recently about a mutual desire to do more &amp;ldquo;giving&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t think either of use really knows what that means to us. This is a really interesting frame for what giving is.
 Philanthropy, then, can be understood as a form of self-expression. It is complementary, not competitive, to government: citizens have the right to use their private assets to experiment with new ideas, and government has the size and longevity to scale and maintain them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-01-31</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-01-31/</guid>
      <description>Articles  A complaint about Google ditching Pixel 3 support. I have a Pixel 3 and sympathize. Google? More like Boo-gle. 👎 As the author says: here I am, with another piece of premature junk, made by the company that pledges to “maximize the reuse of finite resources” and “enable others to do the same&amp;quot;.  Books  I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to Ted Chiang&amp;rsquo;s collection of short stories, Story of Your Life and Others, on Audible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ted Chiang: Story of our life</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/books/story-of-our-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/books/story-of-our-life/</guid>
      <description>Contains spoilers
This was a great novella. A slow burner, it drops its core themes quickly and densely about three quarters of the way through. Language, time, free-will, purpose, parenting are all front and center in this very human human-alien encounter. I love stories that focus on that slippery line between what we have the ability to change and what we don&amp;rsquo;t and how we make sense of this partial self-determination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-18</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-18/</guid>
      <description>Books
Money: The True Story of a Made Up Thing by Jacob Goldstein. By one of the hosts of Planet Money. Short and interesting, made me want to learn more about the Chinese intellectual and scientific advances from around 600 AD to 1200 AD.
Articles
 Acceptance Parenting by Agnes Callard Why are non-alcoholic drinks so expensive? Vancouver is the anti-asian hate crime capital of the world. It&amp;rsquo;s also nearly 30% asian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associative and non-associative learning</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/associative-non-associative/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/associative-non-associative/</guid>
      <description>Associative and non-associative learning From the MIT Open Course Introduction to Psychology
 There are two types of learning: associative learning and non-associative learning. Associative learning is when you learn something new about a new kind of stimulus (that is, an extra stimulus). Non-associative learning is when you&amp;rsquo;re not pairing a stimulus with a behavior. Non-associative learning can be either habituation or sensitization.
Habituation is when repeated exposure to a stimulus decreases an organism&amp;rsquo;s responsiveness to the stimulus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klara and the Sun</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/books/klara-and-the-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/books/klara-and-the-sun/</guid>
      <description>Klara and the sun by Kazuo Ishiguro  If Klara is super intelligent, why doesn&amp;rsquo;t she know basic facts about the sum, solar system, planetary motion, etc? There is clearly some sort of some theology. Is it because the sun is all important to their existence that their creators programmed this strange theology in place of basic science? I realize now after having finished the book what an anthropocentric viewpoint the above comment takes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
