<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Links on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Links on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.colinspear.com/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-22</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-22/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-22   This article on Patrick Collison, Tyler Cowen and Patrick Jay&amp;rsquo;s reflections on the Fast Grants program they started to fund COVID related research during the pandemic. This quote stands out:
 Scientists are in the paradoxical position of being deemed the very best people to fund in order to make important discoveries but not so trustworthy that they should be able to decide what work would actually make the most sense!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-15</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-15/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-15 Books
 A Mind at Play: How Claude Shannon Invented the Information Age. I started this book some time ago, but didn&amp;rsquo;t really get into it. This time, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll finish it. The first part is a mostly personal history, which is interesting, but part two is really where it starts to get good. As someone completely unfamiliar with information theory, the basic concepts are presented very well and clearly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-08</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-08/</guid>
      <description> Simone Biles. What a beast.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-01</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-01/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-01 Reading
 The Honest Broker by Ted Gioia. And they do this for a very simple reason: their prestige is enhanced by making these connections. [&amp;hellip;] the Honest Broker plays the long-term game, mate. He&amp;rsquo;s taking about getting things done as an outsider in China in the nineties, but reputation economies tend to be a vital and underestimated resource in the West too. Thorstein Veblen&amp;rsquo;s Theory of the leisure class - an update This is Rob Henderson&amp;rsquo;s idea that Ellie status is conveyed by displaying a certain set of beliefs in the same way that one might wear a certain hat or handbag or sports car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-25</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-25/</guid>
      <description>Music
 Remember 01 by The Halluci Nation (formerly A Tribe Called Red), an indigenous Canadian hip-hop group based in Ottawa. Another indigenous Canadian musician, Willie Dunn wrote incredble folk songs about native history, culture and western civilization and politics. He has a great voice and his lyrics are 👌. Ballad of Crowfoot is a good place to start and one of his best known songs Mabe Fratti. Moving. A Guatemalan cellist making minimalist electronic cello music in Mexico City.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-18</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-18/</guid>
      <description>Books
Money: The True Story of a Made Up Thing by Jacob Goldstein. By one of the hosts of Planet Money. Short and interesting, made me want to learn more about the Chinese intellectual and scientific advances from around 600 AD to 1200 AD.
Articles
 Acceptance Parenting by Agnes Callard Why are non-alcoholic drinks so expensive? Vancouver is the anti-asian hate crime capital of the world. It&amp;rsquo;s also nearly 30% asian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-10</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-10/</guid>
      <description>Articles
 This Bloomberg article on anti-Asian discrimination in Vancouver The table on the timeline of the Women&amp;rsquo;s Suffrage page on Wikipedia. It&amp;rsquo;s mind-boggling how recently women gained the right to vote. This awesome newsletter entry by Ted Gioia on The Deadliest Song in History. Taking Sex Differences in Personality Seriously  Music
 My Analog Journal. A great YouTube channel that &amp;ldquo;explore rare grooves around the world on vinyl&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of hour long sets, filmed looking straight down at the turntable while he spins.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
