<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Links on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Links on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//www.colinspear.com/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>May 29, 2023</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2023-05-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2023-05-29/</guid>
      <description>Branko Mataja It&amp;rsquo;s musicians like this that make me so grateful that reissue labels like Numero Group exist. Mataja&amp;rsquo;s approach to the guitar would be novel and exciting if he realeased it today, let alone fifty years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s not as if he&amp;rsquo;s going to be topping billboard charts anytime soon, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one who never would have heard of him without a reissue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023-05-16</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2023-05-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2023-05-16/</guid>
      <description>Kevin Kelly is a national treasure It&amp;rsquo;s true. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, here are some of his projects:
 The Technium is his main blog. Cool Tools is what it says it is. Reviews of cool tools of all sorts. Excellent Advice for Living is his latest book, which seems basically like a set of more intelligible and practical koans encapsulating his vision.  These (and tons of other stuff he makes) are cool and all, but it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly the specifics of what he&amp;rsquo;s done / made that inspire me, but more his approach and attitude towards life and living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-06-24</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-06-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-06-10/</guid>
      <description>Music The more I listen, the more I like Kevin Morby&amp;rsquo;s new album, This is a Photograph. The prayer / toast toward the end is especially wonderful:
 to free the flame from burning up inside to thunder like a motorcycle headed down the line to eat to weep to lay me down so sweet to sow to reap oh to let our glasses clink to time to time to time to time to time to time to time to time</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-06-08</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-05-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-05-28/</guid>
      <description>The world is a musem of passion projects
Music  This Ted Gioia newsletter on how TikTok is changing the incentives of the record business, shifting power away from record labels and into the hands of musicians who are able to find success on the platform. I would love to see this blow up into something.  Covid fallout I&amp;rsquo;ve been seeing and reading more about the social and economic effects of Covid and pandemic related actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-05-30</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-28/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts On existential risk and climate change  80,000 hours: Toby Ord on existential risk Volts podcast  Elizabeth Popp Berman Noah Smith Paulina Jaramillo    These are all just loosely related, but I listened to them all around the same time and found it very interesting to hold the arguments and implications in my head together. Putting climate change in perspective (before the 80,000 hours podcast I had just default assumed climate change was a major existential risk) while still acknowledging the extremely destructive impacts of the warming that is likely to happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-03-21</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-21/</guid>
      <description>Articles   Nadia Eghbal&amp;rsquo;s new work sounds really interesting. Hannah and I have been talking recently about a mutual desire to do more &amp;ldquo;giving&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t think either of use really knows what that means to us. This is a really interesting frame for what giving is.
 Philanthropy, then, can be understood as a form of self-expression. It is complementary, not competitive, to government: citizens have the right to use their private assets to experiment with new ideas, and government has the size and longevity to scale and maintain them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-03-07</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-07/</guid>
      <description>Articles   Matt Levine&amp;rsquo;s explanation ot the significance of the west&amp;rsquo;s exclusion of Russia from the international financial system is really good. This is a major precedent in using the international financial system as a weapon of war and the implications are potentially quite expansive. Here&amp;rsquo;s one excerpt (which he laudably precedes with caveats arount the rule of law and the neutrality of money):
 But what I want to suggest is that this weekend’s actions are evidence that the basic structure is good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-28</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-28/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts   This Conversations with Tyler episode with Chuck Klosterman was great. There are a lot of really interesting sections! At the end, Tyler breaks his Very Serious Interviewer mode and they just chat for a while. It&amp;rsquo;s still super interesting and fun to hear something a bit more conversational than ususal. I still love his standard no-nonsense approach though and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want him to change as there is much less of that out there than there is just people chatting about stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-21</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-21/</guid>
      <description>Twitter   Tweets on underrated ideas by Ethan Mollick and Derek Thompson. Makes me want to think about the ideas that have had the biggest influence on my recent thinking/doing. The first ones that comes to mind are:
 Small, consistent effort is much more impactful than major, intermittent effort in the long run. Sunk cost fallacy. I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge fan of the simplistic version of this (never make decisions based on past investments), but find that it can be quite useful to deemphasize the past when making decisions about the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-14</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-14/</guid>
      <description>Happy V-day, lovers.
Podcasts  Season Two, Episode Two of What had happened was has a gem of a section that could easily be turned into a 5,000 word think piece on art, ephemerality and the responsibility we have (or don&amp;rsquo;t) when it comes to preserving art that may just fade into nonexistence under current legal and economic conditions. It&amp;rsquo;s this section where I realized that El-P is seeing the whole chessboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-07</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-07/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts  Open Mike Eagle&amp;rsquo;s What had happened was is a gift to humanity. It&amp;rsquo;s the history of weirdo, independent hip hop from the horse&amp;rsquo;s mouth. Season One with Prince Paul (producer for De la Soul, Stetsasonic, MF Doom, Paul Barman, etc. etc.) was easily one of my favorite podcasts of 2020. I&amp;rsquo;m late to the Season 2 party with El-P (Company Flow, Run the Jewels, etc.), but it&amp;rsquo;s sounding good so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-01-31</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-01-31/</guid>
      <description>Articles  A complaint about Google ditching Pixel 3 support. I have a Pixel 3 and sympathize. Google? More like Boo-gle. 👎 As the author says: here I am, with another piece of premature junk, made by the company that pledges to “maximize the reuse of finite resources” and “enable others to do the same&amp;rdquo;.  Books  I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to Ted Chiang&amp;rsquo;s collection of short stories, Story of Your Life and Others, on Audible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-01-03</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-01-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-01-03/</guid>
      <description>I stopped updating this when I started a new job in October. I think I&amp;rsquo;m settling in a bit and hope to get back to providing weekly or near weekly updates to what I&amp;rsquo;m consuming. I also want to do some best of lists - books, albums, etc. Stay posted.
2022-01-03 Music  Bunny is a Rider by Caroline Polachek. Try not to groove. Acclaimed Music&amp;rsquo;s 10,000 best songs of all-time Spotify playlist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-09-28</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-09-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-09-28/</guid>
      <description>2021-09-28 Tweets GOP sliding into authoritarianism. How is the trend reversed? Or is this a misguided take - is the GOP not actually getting more authoritarian?
Podcasts Amia Srinavasan on Conversations with Tyler. This was an amazing view of how disciplines can talk right past one another. The particularities of what you focus on when thinking about an issue shape how you think abou that issue so much. Very awkward, very good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-09-12</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-09-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-09-12/</guid>
      <description>2021-09-12 Podcasts China talk
I originally came across this podcast as an Adam Tooze fanboy. He&amp;rsquo;s been on as a guest a number of times and his episodes are as insightful and rich as you might imagine, but I listened to a trio of non-Tooze episodes on U.S.-China relations as part of my self-education on China&amp;rsquo;s shifting role in the global economic and political order. I am woefully undereducated in this realm and this podcast is an amazing resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-07-18</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-07-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-07-18/</guid>
      <description>2021-07-18 Podcasts  David Epstein on People I (Mostly) Admire. Most interesting is the discussion on learning and knowledge retention. Ease is almost surely a sign you are not learning as much as you think. The bit on Fermi estimation (i.e. back of the envelope estimating everything) is also something I would like to try and incorporate into my thinking more. Lex Friedman&amp;rsquo;s interview with Roger Reaves is a trip. Laughing about insane torture in a Mexican Prison, running through the hills from federales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-07-11</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-07-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-07-11/</guid>
      <description>Articles  Nabeel Qureshi&amp;rsquo;s Notes on Popper Noah Smith on the Hispanic shift to the right. Come for the political drama, stay for the economic and social mobility charts. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t realized the degree to which Hispanics were moving up in the US. I want to send this other Noah Smith explainer newsletter on why economics isn&amp;rsquo;t just a way for rich folks to excuse themselves from social responsibility to everyone who has ever asked me what I think about stocks when they learn I studied economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-29</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-29/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-29 Articles   “Smoke a fuckin’ fatty, ya fuckin’ Nazi”
 What is nostalgia like, under such historical conditions? I fear any attempt at answering such a question, today, will necessarily come up short. Today this is how we experience nostalgia: we become anchored to an era, and when it dies, when it is subducted under the ground of time, and we are reminded of that every day in the way other people around us are now dressing and talking and being themselves, in some important sense we die too, and live out our days as ghosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-22</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-22/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-22 Articles   This article on Patrick Collison, Tyler Cowen and Patrick Jay&amp;rsquo;s reflections on the Fast Grants program they started to fund COVID related research during the pandemic. This quote stands out:
 Scientists are in the paradoxical position of being deemed the very best people to fund in order to make important discoveries but not so trustworthy that they should be able to decide what work would actually make the most sense!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-15</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-15/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-15 Books
 A Mind at Play: How Claude Shannon Invented the Information Age. I started this book some time ago, but didn&amp;rsquo;t really get into it. This time, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll finish it. The first part is a mostly personal history, which is interesting, but part two is really where it starts to get good. As someone completely unfamiliar with information theory, the basic concepts are presented very well and clearly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-08</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-08/</guid>
      <description> Simone Biles. What a beast.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-01</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-01/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-01 Reading
 The Honest Broker by Ted Gioia. And they do this for a very simple reason: their prestige is enhanced by making these connections. [&amp;hellip;] the Honest Broker plays the long-term game, mate. He&amp;rsquo;s taking about getting things done as an outsider in China in the nineties, but reputation economies tend to be a vital and underestimated resource in the West too. Thorstein Veblen&amp;rsquo;s Theory of the leisure class - an update This is Rob Henderson&amp;rsquo;s idea that Ellie status is conveyed by displaying a certain set of beliefs in the same way that one might wear a certain hat or handbag or sports car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-25</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-25/</guid>
      <description>Music
 Remember 01 by The Halluci Nation (formerly A Tribe Called Red), an indigenous Canadian hip-hop group based in Ottawa. Another indigenous Canadian musician, Willie Dunn wrote incredble folk songs about native history, culture and western civilization and politics. He has a great voice and his lyrics are 👌. Ballad of Crowfoot is a good place to start and one of his best known songs Mabe Fratti. Moving. A Guatemalan cellist making minimalist electronic cello music in Mexico City.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-18</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-18/</guid>
      <description>Books
Money: The True Story of a Made Up Thing by Jacob Goldstein. By one of the hosts of Planet Money. Short and interesting, made me want to learn more about the Chinese intellectual and scientific advances from around 600 AD to 1200 AD.
Articles
 Acceptance Parenting by Agnes Callard Why are non-alcoholic drinks so expensive? Vancouver is the anti-asian hate crime capital of the world. It&amp;rsquo;s also nearly 30% asian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-10</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-10/</guid>
      <description>Articles
 This Bloomberg article on anti-Asian discrimination in Vancouver The table on the timeline of the Women&amp;rsquo;s Suffrage page on Wikipedia. It&amp;rsquo;s mind-boggling how recently women gained the right to vote. This awesome newsletter entry by Ted Gioia on The Deadliest Song in History. Taking Sex Differences in Personality Seriously  Music
 My Analog Journal. A great YouTube channel that &amp;ldquo;explore rare grooves around the world on vinyl&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of hour long sets, filmed looking straight down at the turntable while he spins.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
