<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>music on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>https://www.colinspear.com/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.colinspear.com/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-07</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-07/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts  Open Mike Eagle&amp;lsquo;s What had happened was is a gift to humanity. It&amp;rsquo;s the history of weirdo, independent hip hop from the horse&amp;rsquo;s mouth. Season One with Prince Paul (producer for De la Soul, Stetsasonic, MF Doom, Paul Barman, etc. etc.) was easily one of my favorite podcasts of 2020. I&amp;rsquo;m late to the Season 2 party with El-P (Company Flow, Run the Jewels, etc.), but it&amp;rsquo;s sounding good so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-29</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-29/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-29 Articles   “Smoke a fuckin’ fatty, ya fuckin’ Nazi”
 What is nostalgia like, under such historical conditions? I fear any attempt at answering such a question, today, will necessarily come up short. Today this is how we experience nostalgia: we become anchored to an era, and when it dies, when it is subducted under the ground of time, and we are reminded of that every day in the way other people around us are now dressing and talking and being themselves, in some important sense we die too, and live out our days as ghosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-25</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-25/</guid>
      <description>Music
 Remember 01 by The Halluci Nation (formerly A Tribe Called Red), an indigenous Canadian hip-hop group based in Ottawa. Another indigenous Canadian musician, Willie Dunn wrote incredble folk songs about native history, culture and western civilization and politics. He has a great voice and his lyrics are 👌. Ballad of Crowfoot is a good place to start and one of his best known songs Mabe Fratti. Moving. A Guatemalan cellist making minimalist electronic cello music in Mexico City.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
