<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>https://www.colinspear.com/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.colinspear.com/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-29/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-29 Articles   “Smoke a fuckin’ fatty, ya fuckin’ Nazi”
 What is nostalgia like, under such historical conditions? I fear any attempt at answering such a question, today, will necessarily come up short. Today this is how we experience nostalgia: we become anchored to an era, and when it dies, when it is subducted under the ground of time, and we are reminded of that every day in the way other people around us are now dressing and talking and being themselves, in some important sense we die too, and live out our days as ghosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-25</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-25/</guid>
      <description>Music
 Remember 01 by The Halluci Nation (formerly A Tribe Called Red), an indigenous Canadian hip-hop group based in Ottawa. Another indigenous Canadian musician, Willie Dunn wrote incredble folk songs about native history, culture and western civilization and politics. He has a great voice and his lyrics are 👌. Ballad of Crowfoot is a good place to start and one of his best known songs Mabe Fratti. Moving. A Guatemalan cellist making minimalist electronic cello music in Mexico City.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music: A Subversive History</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/book-notes/music-subversive-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/book-notes/music-subversive-history/</guid>
      <description>Krause describes a memorable encounter with an elder of the Nez Perce tribe named Angus Wilson, who chided him one day: “You white people know nothing about music. But I’ll teach you something about it if you want.” The next morning, Krause found himself led to the bank of a stream in northeastern Oregon, where he was motioned to sit quietly on the ground. After a chilly wait, a breeze picked up, and suddenly his surroundings were filled with the sound of a pipe organ chord—a remarkable occurrence, since no instrument was in sight.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
