<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>confusion on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>https://www.colinspear.com/tags/confusion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in confusion on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.colinspear.com/tags/confusion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Confusion</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/confusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/confusion/</guid>
      <description>Confusion I am working through a task at work of reproducing a dataset using a long SQL script consisting of separate chunks of data manipulation and manual edits (to the data table, not the code). As often happens, documentation is less than perfect and I am left to figure out much of what I am doing in my own. This naturally leads to some confusion - what should I be looking for, how do I find an issue to correct, how should I correct the issue when I find it etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orchestration and Demonstration or How to not be an Awkward Host</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/orchestration-and-demonstration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/orchestration-and-demonstration/</guid>
      <description>I put the questions to some friends of mine gathered for a barbeque today: how do we know what is proper social etiquette. Or maybe, the less boozhy way to put it is, how do we know how to behave around others?
I often feel this most acutely when having people over for a meal, when it comes time to eat. I have been running around - chopping, toasting, tasting, roasting - and all of a sudden it&amp;rsquo;s time to eat and everyone is milling about, chatting, drinking and (hopefully) enjoying themselves, just as guests should be.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
