<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>addiction on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/tags/addiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in addiction on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/tags/addiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-19</title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-19/</guid>
      <description>What are the implications of trying to remain anonymous while trying to be part of the new creator economy?
 There is a new kind of creator economy that is quickly expanding and morphing and dividing and being discussed. Some folks that come to mind that are either creating or speaking about this that come to mind are Nadia Eghbal, David Perell, Anna Gat, Alex Danco, Liminal Warmth, critter I am thinking of some twitter accounts I follow The importance of reputation (Nadia Eghbal and David Perell talk a bit about this on his podcast) and the way production cadences interact with this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-11</title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-11/</guid>
      <description>Associative and non-associative learning From the MIT Open Course Introduction to Psychology
 There are two types of learning: associative learning and non-associative learning. Associative learning is when you learn something new about a new kind of stimulus (that is, an extra stimulus). Non-associative learning is when you&amp;rsquo;re not pairing a stimulus with a behavior. Non-associative learning can be either habituation or sensitization.
Habituation is when repeated exposure to a stimulus decreases an organism&amp;rsquo;s responsiveness to the stimulus.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
