<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>podcasts on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>https://www.colinspear.com/tags/podcasts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in podcasts on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.colinspear.com/tags/podcasts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-14</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-14/</guid>
      <description>Happy V-day, lovers.
Podcasts  Season Two, Episode Two of What had happened was has a gem of a section that could easily be turned into a 5,000 word think piece on art, ephemerality and the responsibility we have (or don&amp;rsquo;t) when it comes to preserving art that may just fade into nonexistence under current legal and economic conditions. It&amp;rsquo;s this section where I realized that El-P is seeing the whole chessboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-07</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-07/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts  Open Mike Eagle&amp;rsquo;s What had happened was is a gift to humanity. It&amp;rsquo;s the history of weirdo, independent hip hop from the horse&amp;rsquo;s mouth. Season One with Prince Paul (producer for De la Soul, Stetsasonic, MF Doom, Paul Barman, etc. etc.) was easily one of my favorite podcasts of 2020. I&amp;rsquo;m late to the Season 2 party with El-P (Company Flow, Run the Jewels, etc.), but it&amp;rsquo;s sounding good so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-25</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-25/</guid>
      <description>Music
 Remember 01 by The Halluci Nation (formerly A Tribe Called Red), an indigenous Canadian hip-hop group based in Ottawa. Another indigenous Canadian musician, Willie Dunn wrote incredble folk songs about native history, culture and western civilization and politics. He has a great voice and his lyrics are 👌. Ballad of Crowfoot is a good place to start and one of his best known songs Mabe Fratti. Moving. A Guatemalan cellist making minimalist electronic cello music in Mexico City.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-18</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-18/</guid>
      <description>Books
Money: The True Story of a Made Up Thing by Jacob Goldstein. By one of the hosts of Planet Money. Short and interesting, made me want to learn more about the Chinese intellectual and scientific advances from around 600 AD to 1200 AD.
Articles
 Acceptance Parenting by Agnes Callard Why are non-alcoholic drinks so expensive? Vancouver is the anti-asian hate crime capital of the world. It&amp;rsquo;s also nearly 30% asian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-10</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-10/</guid>
      <description>Articles
 This Bloomberg article on anti-Asian discrimination in Vancouver The table on the timeline of the Women&amp;rsquo;s Suffrage page on Wikipedia. It&amp;rsquo;s mind-boggling how recently women gained the right to vote. This awesome newsletter entry by Ted Gioia on The Deadliest Song in History. Taking Sex Differences in Personality Seriously  Music
 My Analog Journal. A great YouTube channel that &amp;ldquo;explore rare grooves around the world on vinyl&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of hour long sets, filmed looking straight down at the turntable while he spins.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
