<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peoples on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>https://notes-submodule.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/people/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peoples on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notes-submodule.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://notes-submodule.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/people/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes-submodule.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/people/people/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to figure out how to organize the People section of the website. If you have any ideas or suggestions about how to organize a heterogeneous set of complex, indivisible, objects (i.e. humans), please let me know!
 Weirdos and iconoclasts  Chuck Tingle Quentin Crisp Gwern  A freelance writer and tech guy. Super original and hard to describe briefly.   Dan Reeder  A musician who moved from California to Nuremberg and builds most of the instruments he uses, including recording equipment (computers, amplifiers, microphones and PAs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>https://notes-submodule.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/people/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://notes-submodule.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/people/quotes/</guid>
      <description>Quotes Devon Zuegel on the North Star Podcast:
 Everything is interesting of you build a mental model for it
 Agnes Callard on the Ezra Klein Show, minute 40:
 I think we&amp;rsquo;re way too quick to identify ourselves with the long term goals, especially when we are not in the moment of being tempted. So we can say, look I know how I should really live. I know that I should really read those books, and I should not not eat the cookies and I should be less stressed about these things; I should spend more time with my family.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
