<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>notes on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>//www.colinspear.com/tags/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notes on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//www.colinspear.com/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>bash</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/bash/</guid>
      <description>At the moment, this is just a dumping ground for useful tidbits I find / need in my daily work. At some point I will get around to organizing and formalizing.
Parameter Expansion Bash reference manual
Slice a string
a=&amp;#34;teleport&amp;#34; b=${a:4:7} echo $b &amp;gt; port Replace a portion of a string
The pattern is ${parameter/pattern/string} to replace the first occurence of pattern with string or ${parameter//pattern/string} to replace all occurrences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vim</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/vim/</guid>
      <description>At the moment, this is just a dumping ground for useful tidbits I find / need in my daily work. At some point I will get around to organizing and formalizing.
File formats (carriage returns) If you ever diff two files that look identical, but they display as completely different, you may be dealing with a file format issue. This may happen if you are sharing files between different OS. To display the file format of your current file type this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>awk</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/awk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/awk/</guid>
      <description>Basic syntax awk [ options ] script filename Where script is either a single awk command or file of awk commands. Awk commands look like this:
TODO and filename can be omitted if you&amp;rsquo;re piping in standard input.
Commands Options Examples Length of the longest line in a file awk &amp;#39;{ if (length($0) &amp;gt; max) max = length($0) }; END { print max }&amp;#39; file Selecting, filtering, and basic arithmetic Sum a field, specify delimiter awk -F &amp;#39;\t&amp;#39; &amp;#39;{print sum+=$1;} END {print sum}&amp;#39; file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sed</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/sed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/sed/</guid>
      <description>This is an ongoing work in progress, please let me know if you have any suggestions/feedback.
Basic syntax sed [ options ] script filename Where script is either a single sed command or file of sed commands (must use with -f option). Sed commands look like this:
command/pattern/replacement/command and filename can be omitted if you&amp;rsquo;re piping in standard input.
Commands  p: print s: substitute d: delete line  Options  -e: reads the following argument as a script (allows for multiple instructions to be passed at once) -n: don&amp;rsquo;t print to the terminal  Examples Print lines matching a pattern to stdout:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-22</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-22/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-22 Articles   This article on Patrick Collison, Tyler Cowen and Patrick Jay&amp;rsquo;s reflections on the Fast Grants program they started to fund COVID related research during the pandemic. This quote stands out:
 Scientists are in the paradoxical position of being deemed the very best people to fund in order to make important discoveries but not so trustworthy that they should be able to decide what work would actually make the most sense!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confusion</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/confusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/confusion/</guid>
      <description>Confusion I am working through a task at work of reproducing a dataset using a long SQL script consisting of separate chunks of data manipulation and manual edits (to the data table, not the code). As often happens, documentation is less than perfect and I am left to figure out much of what I am doing in my own. This naturally leads to some confusion - what should I be looking for, how do I find an issue to correct, how should I correct the issue when I find it etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orchestration and Demonstration or How to not be an Awkward Host</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/orchestration-and-demonstration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/orchestration-and-demonstration/</guid>
      <description>I put the questions to some friends of mine gathered for a barbeque today: how do we know what is proper social etiquette. Or maybe, the less boozhy way to put it is, how do we know how to behave around others?
I often feel this most acutely when having people over for a meal, when it comes time to eat. I have been running around - chopping, toasting, tasting, roasting - and all of a sudden it&amp;rsquo;s time to eat and everyone is milling about, chatting, drinking and (hopefully) enjoying themselves, just as guests should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/focus/</guid>
      <description>Focus To what extent can we manufacture focus (asking for a friend :tongue_in_cheek_emoji:)
Canonical answers:
 Develop habits (if you get used to doing the same thing every day out will get easier to do the same thing every day) Organize your physical environment to minimize distraction and promote concentration Minimize your ambition set (i.e. Don&amp;rsquo;t have to many goals) Take care of your mental and physical needs (sleep, exercise, etc)  My strategy:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
