<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Technical-posts on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technical-posts on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>git status - fatal: cannot chdir</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/git-submodule-fatal-cannot-chdir/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/git-submodule-fatal-cannot-chdir/</guid>
      <description>tldr: If you make any changes to the file path of a git submodule, you need to also update all of your config files accordingly.
Background I use the Papermod Hugo theme for my personal website. One of the ways to use Hugo themes is to install them as a submodule inside your project&amp;rsquo;s ./themes directory. I wanted to update the module today as there have been a number of changes since I set it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bash</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/bash/</guid>
      <description>At the moment, this is just a dumping ground for useful tidbits I find / need in my daily work. At some point I will get around to organizing and formalizing.
Parameter Expansion Bash reference manual
Slice a string
a=&amp;#34;teleport&amp;#34; b=${a:4:7} echo $b &amp;gt; port Replace a portion of a string
The pattern is ${parameter/pattern/string} to replace the first occurence of pattern with string or ${parameter//pattern/string} to replace all occurrences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vim</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/vim/</guid>
      <description>At the moment, this is just a dumping ground for useful tidbits I find / need in my daily work. At some point I will get around to organizing and formalizing.
File formats (carriage returns) If you ever diff two files that look identical, but they display as completely different, you may be dealing with a file format issue. This may happen if you are sharing files between different OS. To display the file format of your current file type this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>awk</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/awk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/awk/</guid>
      <description>Basic syntax awk [ options ] script filename Where script is either a single awk command or file of awk commands. Awk commands look like this:
TODO and filename can be omitted if you&amp;rsquo;re piping in standard input.
Commands Options Examples Length of the longest line in a file awk &amp;#39;{ if (length($0) &amp;gt; max) max = length($0) }; END { print max }&amp;#39; file Selecting, filtering, and basic arithmetic Sum a field, specify delimiter awk -F &amp;#39;\t&amp;#39; &amp;#39;{print sum+=$1;} END {print sum}&amp;#39; file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sed</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/sed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/sed/</guid>
      <description>This is an ongoing work in progress, please let me know if you have any suggestions/feedback.
Basic syntax sed [ options ] script filename Where script is either a single sed command or file of sed commands (must use with -f option). Sed commands look like this:
command/pattern/replacement/command and filename can be omitted if you&amp;rsquo;re piping in standard input.
Commands  p: print s: substitute d: delete line  Options  -e: reads the following argument as a script (allows for multiple instructions to be passed at once) -n: don&amp;rsquo;t print to the terminal  Examples Print lines matching a pattern to stdout:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change git branch (master to main)</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/change-master-to-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/change-master-to-main/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s another thing I&amp;rsquo;ve googled enough times to just put it somewhere I know.
First, rename your local branch:
❯ git branch -m master main Then you can check that it worked:
❯ git status On branch main Your branch is up to date with &amp;#39;origin/master&amp;#39;. nothing to commit, working tree clean If you don&amp;rsquo;t have dependencies that might get screwed up by simply renaming your master branch, you can just navigate to your remote directory and change the name (if you use github, from the repo&amp;rsquo;s home page, click Settings &amp;gt; Branches and then click the edit button that looks like a little pencil).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flask wordcount app</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/simple_flask_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/simple_flask_app/</guid>
      <description>I made a simple flask app that takes a URL as input and returns a table and chart of the most used words on the site.
Built with Flask using a Postgres backend. Uses beautiful soup to scrape and process html from given website. Implements a Redis task queue to handle requests. Uses Angular to poll the back end for completion and to display a word frequency chart using JavaScript and D3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change your file permissions, baby!</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/chmod_codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 08:28:54 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/chmod_codes/</guid>
      <description>Knowing how to set file permissions is very useful (for a much more thorough primer than I provied here, see this article). Unfortunately, while this is very easy to do, it is even easier to forget the codes used to do so. So here&amp;rsquo;s how you do it!
The easiest (shortest) way to change permissions is using octal syntax. Octal syntax goes like this:
chmod &amp;lt;owner&amp;gt;&amp;lt;group&amp;gt;&amp;lt;others&amp;gt; filename Where &amp;lt;owner&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;group&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;others&amp;gt; stand for the octal numeral pertaining to that user or group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move and rename all files in a folder</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/cl_move_and_rename_files/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 12:49:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/cl_move_and_rename_files/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to move and rename a bunch of excel files in a folder. This is one way to do it from the command line, copying into a directory in the parent folder. I did it this way to be able to rm -r old_folder after copying my files to the new folder. You could modify it to rename them in place, but I&amp;rsquo;ve accidentally rm -rfed enough things to get nervous doing it that way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Count files by type and directory</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/count-files-by-type-and-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/count-files-by-type-and-directory/</guid>
      <description>Using the command line to count stuff</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
