<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 20:23:04 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/stoicism-vs-sentimentalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 20:23:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/stoicism-vs-sentimentalism/</guid>
      <description>Stoicism vs Sentimentalism Use Agnes Callard&amp;rsquo;s On Anger as an argument against rationality. In this view the truly rational thing is to hold a grudge and exact revenge forever and ever, amen. It is the irrational dissolution of anger that allows for peace and resolution</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/performance-ambivalence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 20:41:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/performance-ambivalence/</guid>
      <description># Craft or crap? The tension between striving and embracing who we are Links  Nietsche vs Kierkegaard Tim Ferris and Brene Brown  When I was much younger, after dropping out of high school in a THC-drenched haze, I spent a lot of time meditating and reading about meditation and buddhist flavored self improvement. I loved it and took it seriously, had a regular practice, attended a regular group meditation, went on retreat and diligently studied the modern western buddhist canon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/randomization-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 21:32:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/randomization-inference/</guid>
      <description>References
 Section in Causal Inference, the mixtape Abadie, Athey paper  Randomization inference Just want to think a bit about what I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about randomization inference
It is an alternative, experiment inspired framework for thinking about and performing causal inference
 Cunningham treats it mostly like a robustness test (from what I can tell) outside of limited contexts, and still maybe in the most appropriate contexts as it&amp;rsquo;s not super mainstream for example, they say that it&amp;rsquo;s especially useful for situations in which, instead of working with a random sample of a population, there is good reason to believe you are working with the entire population itself what does this mean for external validity?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
