<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Colin Spear</title>
    <link>//www.colinspear.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//www.colinspear.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Similar artist network</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/artist_graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/artist_graph/</guid>
      <description>Motivation If you are anything like me, you occasionally find yourself coming up for air after a long diversion clicking through artist biographies on Spotify. Often these biographies will list the artists other bands or people they have played with, and one thing leads to another and I have added twenty albums to my &amp;ldquo;new music&amp;rdquo; playlist folder.
I found myself in this position one morning after listening to this episode of Casual Inference, a great podcast that has unfortunately gone radio silent of late.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python sucks at basic data visualization</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/python-visualization-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/python-visualization-sucks/</guid>
      <description>Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s hyperbolic, but it&amp;rsquo;s not wrong I recently saw the following tweet comparing the Canadian and US housing markets.
   As an American Canadian permanent resident who experiences this phenomenon acutely, I was naturaly interested. What particularly got my attention was the claim in one of the comments that this was &amp;ldquo;70% Toronto and Vancouver&amp;rdquo;. I thought, &amp;ldquo;I wonder if I can verify that&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;.
So I went to the Statistics Canada website and found the New housing price index which has monthly data on the cost of new housing going back to 1981 for 26 cities across the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/lists/record-labels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/lists/record-labels/</guid>
      <description>Reissue labels Numero group
 From their website:   A brief overview of the governing series within our greater catalog:
 Eccentric Soul - Our flagship series that documents lost soul music Wayfaring Strangers - Compiles privately issued folk music Cult Cargo - Unearths the music of remote island nations Good God! - Praises obscure gospel and spiritual tunes Local Customs - Investigations of mom-and-pop recording outfits 200 Line - Explores punk, hardcore, and artistic rock from the ’80s and ’90s   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 29, 2023</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2023-05-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2023-05-29/</guid>
      <description>Branko Mataja It&amp;rsquo;s musicians like this that make me so grateful that reissue labels like Numero Group exist. Mataja&amp;rsquo;s approach to the guitar would be novel and exciting if he realeased it today, let alone fifty years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s not as if he&amp;rsquo;s going to be topping billboard charts anytime soon, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one who never would have heard of him without a reissue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023 Book list</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/2023-book-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/2023-book-list/</guid>
      <description>Finished  Alias Grace, Margaret Atwood Fall on Your Knees, Ann-Marie Macdonald Neapolitan Novels, Elena Ferrante Babel, R.F. Kuang Anna Karenina, Leo Tolstoy  Started  The Jade Peony, Wayson Choy 2666, Roberto Bolaño Mythos, Stephen Fry Faith, Hope and Carnage, Nick Cave and Sean O&amp;rsquo;hagan Of Boys and Men, Richard Reeves David Copperfield, Charles Dickens Super-Infinite, Katherine Rundell A Heart So White, Javier Marias The Screwtape Letters, C.S. Lewis  Ongoing / Non-narrative  The Complete Poems &amp;amp; Plays, T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023-05-16</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2023-05-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2023-05-16/</guid>
      <description>Kevin Kelly is a national treasure It&amp;rsquo;s true. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, here are some of his projects:
 The Technium is his main blog. Cool Tools is what it says it is. Reviews of cool tools of all sorts. Excellent Advice for Living is his latest book, which seems basically like a set of more intelligible and practical koans encapsulating his vision.  These (and tons of other stuff he makes) are cool and all, but it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly the specifics of what he&amp;rsquo;s done / made that inspire me, but more his approach and attitude towards life and living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where I&#39;m Calling From, Raymond Carver</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/where-im-calling-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/where-im-calling-from/</guid>
      <description>Frank Martin uncrosses his arms and takes a puff on the cigar. He lets the smoke carry out of his mouth. Then he raises his chin toward the hills and says, &amp;ldquo;Jack London used to have a big place on the other side of this valley. Right over there, behind that green hill you&amp;rsquo;re looking at. But alchohol killed him. Let that be a lesson. He was a better man than any of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-06-24</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-06-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-06-10/</guid>
      <description>Music The more I listen, the more I like Kevin Morby&amp;rsquo;s new album, This is a Photograph. The prayer / toast toward the end is especially wonderful:
 to free the flame from burning up inside to thunder like a motorcycle headed down the line to eat to weep to lay me down so sweet to sow to reap oh to let our glasses clink to time to time to time to time to time to time to time to time</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sea of Tranquility</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/sea-of-tranquility/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/sea-of-tranquility/</guid>
      <description>Why did Gaspery-Jacques get sent to Ohio where he happened to run into Mirella? It wasn&amp;rsquo;t his decision, was it? Why would the Time Institute want to do that? Was it an accident? It seems too unlikely to be an accident&amp;hellip;
 I think, as a species, we have a desire to believe that we’re living at the climax of the story. It’s a kind of narcissism. We want to believe that we’re uniquely important, that we’re living at the end of history, that now, after all these millennia of false alarms, now is finally the worst that it’s ever been, that finally we have reached the end of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 Books</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/2022-book-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/2022-book-list/</guid>
      <description>Finished  Recursion, Blake Crouch ⭐⭐⭐ Story of our life, Ted Chiang ⭐⭐⭐ Five Little Indians, Michelle Good ⭐⭐ Never Let Me Go, Kazuo Ishiguro ⭐⭐⭐⭐ Exit West, Mohsin Hamid ⭐⭐⭐⭐⭐ The English Patient, Michael Ondaatje ⭐⭐⭐⭐ The Anomaly, Herve Le Tellier ⭐⭐⭐⭐⭐ American Gods, Neil Gaiman ⭐⭐⭐ Sea of Tranquility, Emily St. John Mandel ⭐⭐⭐⭐ Cloud Atlas, David Mitchell How to Write One Song, Jeff Tweedy The Odyssey, Homer  Unfinished &amp;gt;50% complete  The Inconvenient Indian, Thomas King ⭐⭐⭐ Shutdown, Adam Tooze ⭐⭐  &amp;lt;50% complete  Crashed, Adam Tooze Neuromancer, William Gibson Split Tooth, Tanya Tagaq Beloved, Toni Morrison Sutree, Cormac McCarthy  Check out The following are from this Hacker News thread:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-06-08</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-05-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-05-28/</guid>
      <description>The world is a musem of passion projects
Music  This Ted Gioia newsletter on how TikTok is changing the incentives of the record business, shifting power away from record labels and into the hands of musicians who are able to find success on the platform. I would love to see this blow up into something.  Covid fallout I&amp;rsquo;ve been seeing and reading more about the social and economic effects of Covid and pandemic related actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exit West, Mohsin Hamid</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/exit-west/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/exit-west/</guid>
      <description>A quote highlighted by Colleen:
 By the time he entered university, Saeed’s parents prayed more often than they had when he was younger, maybe because they had lost a great many loved ones by that age, or maybe because the transient natures of their own lives were gradually becoming less hidden from them, or maybe because they worried for their son in a country that seemed to worship money above all, no matter how much other forms of worship were given lip service, or maybe simply because their personal relationships with prayer had deepened and become more meaningful over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/quotes/</guid>
      <description>From Maclean&amp;rsquo;s article:
 Averages don’t capture the steepest declines, a point made colourfully by the head of the New Hampshire-based Center for Assessment. “We have a saying in New England,” Scott Marion told Education Week. “You can have one foot on a wood stove, and another on a block of ice, and on average you’re pretty comfortable.”
 Kevin Morby on his album, This is a Photograph:
 to free the flame from burning up inside to thunder like a motorcycle headed down the line to eat to weep to lay me down so sweet to sow to reap oh to let our glasses clink to time to time to time to time to time to time to time to time</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Ending Fire, Wendell Berry</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/world-ending-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/world-ending-fire/</guid>
      <description>This book really pits two of my beliefs against one another. On the one hand, I believe the value of specific, physical places and our relationships with them is vastly underrated. It provides meaning, connects us to the past and encourages a deep respect for people and places that is a necessary counterweight to the obvious trends of the ephemeral, impersonal nature of our modern digitized lives. It is the place from which all efforts at conservation should begin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-05-30</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-28/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts On existential risk and climate change  80,000 hours: Toby Ord on existential risk Volts podcast  Elizabeth Popp Berman Noah Smith Paulina Jaramillo    These are all just loosely related, but I listened to them all around the same time and found it very interesting to hold the arguments and implications in my head together. Putting climate change in perspective (before the 80,000 hours podcast I had just default assumed climate change was a major existential risk) while still acknowledging the extremely destructive impacts of the warming that is likely to happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git status - fatal: cannot chdir</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/git-submodule-fatal-cannot-chdir/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/git-submodule-fatal-cannot-chdir/</guid>
      <description>tldr: If you make any changes to the file path of a git submodule, you need to also update all of your config files accordingly.
Background I use the Papermod Hugo theme for my personal website. One of the ways to use Hugo themes is to install them as a submodule inside your project&amp;rsquo;s ./themes directory. I wanted to update the module today as there have been a number of changes since I set it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The English Patient</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/english-patient/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/english-patient/</guid>
      <description>7% : The winds of the world known by the patient. It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely passage. The Wikipedia page on the winds of the world is not nearly as beautiful, but also very cool.
30% : The sapper. The man who defused the landmines left behind by the retreating German military. Kip.
42% : Their distance gives them a private energy. Was this the inspiration for the Helado Negro album?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/git/</guid>
      <description>Pull changes in from master that have happened since making changes on feature branch git checkout feature git rebase master Merge feature branch into master To merge a feature into master, first commit changes to your feature branch, then:
git checkout master git pull origin master git merge feature git push origin master See history git log to see all. Include file if you only want to see history for that file: git log [filename]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-03-21</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-21/</guid>
      <description>Articles   Nadia Eghbal&amp;rsquo;s new work sounds really interesting. Hannah and I have been talking recently about a mutual desire to do more &amp;ldquo;giving&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t think either of use really knows what that means to us. This is a really interesting frame for what giving is.
 Philanthropy, then, can be understood as a form of self-expression. It is complementary, not competitive, to government: citizens have the right to use their private assets to experiment with new ideas, and government has the size and longevity to scale and maintain them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bash</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/bash/</guid>
      <description>At the moment, this is just a dumping ground for useful tidbits I find / need in my daily work. At some point I will get around to organizing and formalizing.
Parameter Expansion Bash reference manual
Slice a string
a=&amp;#34;teleport&amp;#34; b=${a:4:7} echo $b &amp;gt; port Replace a portion of a string
The pattern is ${parameter/pattern/string} to replace the first occurence of pattern with string or ${parameter//pattern/string} to replace all occurrences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vim</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/vim/</guid>
      <description>At the moment, this is just a dumping ground for useful tidbits I find / need in my daily work. At some point I will get around to organizing and formalizing.
File formats (carriage returns) If you ever diff two files that look identical, but they display as completely different, you may be dealing with a file format issue. This may happen if you are sharing files between different OS. To display the file format of your current file type this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-03-07</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-03-07/</guid>
      <description>Articles   Matt Levine&amp;rsquo;s explanation ot the significance of the west&amp;rsquo;s exclusion of Russia from the international financial system is really good. This is a major precedent in using the international financial system as a weapon of war and the implications are potentially quite expansive. Here&amp;rsquo;s one excerpt (which he laudably precedes with caveats arount the rule of law and the neutrality of money):
 But what I want to suggest is that this weekend’s actions are evidence that the basic structure is good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-28</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-28/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts   This Conversations with Tyler episode with Chuck Klosterman was great. There are a lot of really interesting sections! At the end, Tyler breaks his Very Serious Interviewer mode and they just chat for a while. It&amp;rsquo;s still super interesting and fun to hear something a bit more conversational than ususal. I still love his standard no-nonsense approach though and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want him to change as there is much less of that out there than there is just people chatting about stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-21</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-21/</guid>
      <description>Twitter   Tweets on underrated ideas by Ethan Mollick and Derek Thompson. Makes me want to think about the ideas that have had the biggest influence on my recent thinking/doing. The first ones that comes to mind are:
 Small, consistent effort is much more impactful than major, intermittent effort in the long run. Sunk cost fallacy. I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge fan of the simplistic version of this (never make decisions based on past investments), but find that it can be quite useful to deemphasize the past when making decisions about the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-14</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-14/</guid>
      <description>Happy V-day, lovers.
Podcasts  Season Two, Episode Two of What had happened was has a gem of a section that could easily be turned into a 5,000 word think piece on art, ephemerality and the responsibility we have (or don&amp;rsquo;t) when it comes to preserving art that may just fade into nonexistence under current legal and economic conditions. It&amp;rsquo;s this section where I realized that El-P is seeing the whole chessboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-07</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-07/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts  Open Mike Eagle&amp;rsquo;s What had happened was is a gift to humanity. It&amp;rsquo;s the history of weirdo, independent hip hop from the horse&amp;rsquo;s mouth. Season One with Prince Paul (producer for De la Soul, Stetsasonic, MF Doom, Paul Barman, etc. etc.) was easily one of my favorite podcasts of 2020. I&amp;rsquo;m late to the Season 2 party with El-P (Company Flow, Run the Jewels, etc.), but it&amp;rsquo;s sounding good so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>awk</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/awk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/awk/</guid>
      <description>Basic syntax awk [ options ] script filenameWhere script is either a single awk command or file of awk commands. Awk commands look like this:
TODOand filename can be omitted if you&amp;rsquo;re piping in standard input.
Commands Options Examples Length of the longest line in a file awk &amp;#39;{ if (length($0) &amp;gt; max) max = length($0) }; END { print max }&amp;#39; fileSelecting, filtering, and basic arithmetic Sum a field, specify delimiter awk -F &amp;#39;\t&amp;#39; &amp;#39;{print sum+=$1;} END {print sum}&amp;#39; file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-01-31</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-01-31/</guid>
      <description>Articles  A complaint about Google ditching Pixel 3 support. I have a Pixel 3 and sympathize. Google? More like Boo-gle. 👎 As the author says: here I am, with another piece of premature junk, made by the company that pledges to “maximize the reuse of finite resources” and “enable others to do the same&amp;rdquo;.  Books  I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to Ted Chiang&amp;rsquo;s collection of short stories, Story of Your Life and Others, on Audible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sed</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/sed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/sed/</guid>
      <description>This is an ongoing work in progress, please let me know if you have any suggestions/feedback.
Basic syntax sed [ options ] script filenameWhere script is either a single sed command or file of sed commands (must use with -f option). Sed commands look like this:
action/pattern/replacement/flagFilename can be omitted if you&amp;rsquo;re piping in standard input.
Actions  p: print s: substitute  s accepts the following flags which are appended to the end of the command (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ted Chiang: Story of our life</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/story-of-our-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/story-of-our-life/</guid>
      <description>Contains spoilers
This was a great novella. A slow burner, it drops its core themes quickly and densely about three quarters of the way through. Language, time, free-will, purpose, parenting are all front and center in this very human human-alien encounter. I love stories that focus on that slippery line between what we have the ability to change and what we don&amp;rsquo;t and how we make sense of this partial self-determination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-01-03</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-01-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2022-01-03/</guid>
      <description>I stopped updating this when I started a new job in October. I think I&amp;rsquo;m settling in a bit and hope to get back to providing weekly or near weekly updates to what I&amp;rsquo;m consuming. I also want to do some best of lists - books, albums, etc. Stay posted.
2022-01-03 Music  Bunny is a Rider by Caroline Polachek. Try not to groove. Acclaimed Music&amp;rsquo;s 10,000 best songs of all-time Spotify playlist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-09-28</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-09-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-09-28/</guid>
      <description>2021-09-28 Tweets GOP sliding into authoritarianism. How is the trend reversed? Or is this a misguided take - is the GOP not actually getting more authoritarian?
Podcasts Amia Srinavasan on Conversations with Tyler. This was an amazing view of how disciplines can talk right past one another. The particularities of what you focus on when thinking about an issue shape how you think abou that issue so much. Very awkward, very good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-09-12</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-09-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-09-12/</guid>
      <description>2021-09-12 Podcasts China talk
I originally came across this podcast as an Adam Tooze fanboy. He&amp;rsquo;s been on as a guest a number of times and his episodes are as insightful and rich as you might imagine, but I listened to a trio of non-Tooze episodes on U.S.-China relations as part of my self-education on China&amp;rsquo;s shifting role in the global economic and political order. I am woefully undereducated in this realm and this podcast is an amazing resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orwell - Essays</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/orwell-essays/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/orwell-essays/</guid>
      <description>Essays by George Orwell So much of his worldview seems to be about his experience of violence and the political context in which he experienced it.
The scale and scope of violence that was part of European life in the first half of the 20th century is so hard to fathom. Reading Orwell really drives home the idea that this experience was such a formative part of not just political, financial and public life, but the way in which people forged their beliefs and their sense of self - who they were in the world and the ways in which they understood themselves and their role in society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-07-18</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-07-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-07-18/</guid>
      <description>2021-07-18 Podcasts  David Epstein on People I (Mostly) Admire. Most interesting is the discussion on learning and knowledge retention. Ease is almost surely a sign you are not learning as much as you think. The bit on Fermi estimation (i.e. back of the envelope estimating everything) is also something I would like to try and incorporate into my thinking more. Lex Friedman&amp;rsquo;s interview with Roger Reaves is a trip. Laughing about insane torture in a Mexican Prison, running through the hills from federales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-07-11</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-07-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-07-11/</guid>
      <description>Articles  Nabeel Qureshi&amp;rsquo;s Notes on Popper Noah Smith on the Hispanic shift to the right. Come for the political drama, stay for the economic and social mobility charts. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t realized the degree to which Hispanics were moving up in the US. I want to send this other Noah Smith explainer newsletter on why economics isn&amp;rsquo;t just a way for rich folks to excuse themselves from social responsibility to everyone who has ever asked me what I think about stocks when they learn I studied economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-29</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-29/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-29 Articles   “Smoke a fuckin’ fatty, ya fuckin’ Nazi”
 What is nostalgia like, under such historical conditions? I fear any attempt at answering such a question, today, will necessarily come up short. Today this is how we experience nostalgia: we become anchored to an era, and when it dies, when it is subducted under the ground of time, and we are reminded of that every day in the way other people around us are now dressing and talking and being themselves, in some important sense we die too, and live out our days as ghosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journals, magazines and other online aggregations</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/journal-magazine-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/journal-magazine-list/</guid>
      <description> Works in Progress The Public Domain Review Gapminder (Dollarstreet) Our World in Data Cochrane Library - summaries of state of knowledge based on RCTs  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-22</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-22/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-22 Articles   This article on Patrick Collison, Tyler Cowen and Patrick Jay&amp;rsquo;s reflections on the Fast Grants program they started to fund COVID related research during the pandemic. This quote stands out:
 Scientists are in the paradoxical position of being deemed the very best people to fund in order to make important discoveries but not so trustworthy that they should be able to decide what work would actually make the most sense!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-15</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-15/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-15 Books
 A Mind at Play: How Claude Shannon Invented the Information Age. I started this book some time ago, but didn&amp;rsquo;t really get into it. This time, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll finish it. The first part is a mostly personal history, which is interesting, but part two is really where it starts to get good. As someone completely unfamiliar with information theory, the basic concepts are presented very well and clearly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing the work &gt; Preparing for the work</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/performance-ambivalence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/performance-ambivalence/</guid>
      <description>Links  Tyler Cowen and David Perell Anna Gat Music: A Subversive History Agnes Callard on the Ezra Klein Show Me, being oh so witty  Motivating questions  How do we know when to push and when to rest, both at the micro level (e.g. in daily/weekly subproject level) and at the macro level (e.g. what projects to take on, when to quit a project)? What is the relationship between striving and acceptance?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On being nice</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/being-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/being-nice/</guid>
      <description>My comparative advantage (the craft of being nice :face_with_open_mouth_vomiting:🤢) It&amp;rsquo;s not often you see your CFO holding back tears. It&amp;rsquo;s even rarer when the reason he&amp;rsquo;s doing so is because you&amp;rsquo;re being fired.
No, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t part of a mass layoff or a restructuring or a merger or anything like that. I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t very good at my job. We all knew it and I had already been interviewing at other places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-08</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-08/</guid>
      <description> Simone Biles. What a beast.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mind at Play: How Claude Shannon Invented the Information Age</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/a-mind-at-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/a-mind-at-play/</guid>
      <description>A Mind at Play: How Claude Shannon Invented the Information Age by Jimmy Sony &amp;amp; Rob Goodman Information is divorced from content. This was one of the fundamental insights leading up to Shannon&amp;rsquo;s work. Information is not about what you send, it&amp;rsquo;s simply about what you can send, or the set of things you can send. This is kind of amazing to me: developing the technologies that have given us so many platforms for expressing our weirdness and individuality was only possible by ignoring all of that stuff in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conjectures and Refutations</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/conjectures-refutations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/conjectures-refutations/</guid>
      <description>Conjectures and Refutations by Karl Popper  Contrasts the Empiricists (the philosophers that saw truth as something stemming from natural observation) with the rationalists (those that believed truth is something to be found through intellectual intuition) His argument is that both of these camps are not really that different at all. They both believe truth to be something whole that can be obtained in full in one way or the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leondardo da Vinci</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/da-vinci-isaacson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/da-vinci-isaacson/</guid>
      <description>Leonardo da Vinci by Walter Isaacson Introduction  That followed Leonardo&amp;rsquo;s injunction to begin any investigation by going to the source: he who can go to the fountain does not go to the water jar.
 Themes  Iteration and going deeper. The revisiting if the painting&amp;rsquo;s neck twenty years after the initial painting to correctly render the two sternocleidomastoid muscles after human dissection in 1510. Beginning from foundations. First you must paint the skeleton, then move outward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-01</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-01/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-01 Reading
 The Honest Broker by Ted Gioia. And they do this for a very simple reason: their prestige is enhanced by making these connections. [&amp;hellip;] the Honest Broker plays the long-term game, mate. He&amp;rsquo;s taking about getting things done as an outsider in China in the nineties, but reputation economies tend to be a vital and underestimated resource in the West too. Thorstein Veblen&amp;rsquo;s Theory of the leisure class - an update This is Rob Henderson&amp;rsquo;s idea that Ellie status is conveyed by displaying a certain set of beliefs in the same way that one might wear a certain hat or handbag or sports car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tristes Tropiques</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/triste-tropique/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/triste-tropique/</guid>
      <description>Tristes Tropiques&amp;rsquo; by Claude Levi-Strauss  Mankind has opted for monoculture
 From early in the book, perhaps from the introduction. I don&amp;rsquo;t recall precisely.
Chapter 9   The ground that his observations cover is truly remarkable. In chapter 9, Guanabara, he goes from travelogue to France&amp;rsquo;s early colonial history in Brazil to urban design over the course of only a few paragraphs.
  He speaks of the way that places have ceased to shock and surprise in the way they once did before the sustained contact between colonial and native cultures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-25</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-25/</guid>
      <description>Music
 Remember 01 by The Halluci Nation (formerly A Tribe Called Red), an indigenous Canadian hip-hop group based in Ottawa. Another indigenous Canadian musician, Willie Dunn wrote incredble folk songs about native history, culture and western civilization and politics. He has a great voice and his lyrics are 👌. Ballad of Crowfoot is a good place to start and one of his best known songs Mabe Fratti. Moving. A Guatemalan cellist making minimalist electronic cello music in Mexico City.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confusion</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/confusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/confusion/</guid>
      <description>Confusion I am working through a task at work of reproducing a dataset using a long SQL script consisting of separate chunks of data manipulation and manual edits (to the data table, not the code). As often happens, documentation is less than perfect and I am left to figure out much of what I am doing in my own. This naturally leads to some confusion - what should I be looking for, how do I find an issue to correct, how should I correct the issue when I find it etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orchestration and Demonstration or How to not be an Awkward Host</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/orchestration-and-demonstration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/orchestration-and-demonstration/</guid>
      <description>I put the questions to some friends of mine gathered for a barbeque today: how do we know what is proper social etiquette. Or maybe, the less boozhy way to put it is, how do we know how to behave around others?
I often feel this most acutely when having people over for a meal, when it comes time to eat. I have been running around - chopping, toasting, tasting, roasting - and all of a sudden it&amp;rsquo;s time to eat and everyone is milling about, chatting, drinking and (hopefully) enjoying themselves, just as guests should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-18</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-18/</guid>
      <description>Books
Money: The True Story of a Made Up Thing by Jacob Goldstein. By one of the hosts of Planet Money. Short and interesting, made me want to learn more about the Chinese intellectual and scientific advances from around 600 AD to 1200 AD.
Articles
 Acceptance Parenting by Agnes Callard Why are non-alcoholic drinks so expensive? Vancouver is the anti-asian hate crime capital of the world. It&amp;rsquo;s also nearly 30% asian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/focus/</guid>
      <description>Focus To what extent can we manufacture focus (asking for a friend :tongue_in_cheek_emoji:)
Canonical answers:
 Develop habits (if you get used to doing the same thing every day out will get easier to do the same thing every day) Organize your physical environment to minimize distraction and promote concentration Minimize your ambition set (i.e. Don&amp;rsquo;t have to many goals) Take care of your mental and physical needs (sleep, exercise, etc)  My strategy:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associative and non-associative learning</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/associative-non-associative/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/thoughts-posts/associative-non-associative/</guid>
      <description>Associative and non-associative learning From the MIT Open Course Introduction to Psychology
 There are two types of learning: associative learning and non-associative learning. Associative learning is when you learn something new about a new kind of stimulus (that is, an extra stimulus). Non-associative learning is when you&amp;rsquo;re not pairing a stimulus with a behavior. Non-associative learning can be either habituation or sensitization.
Habituation is when repeated exposure to a stimulus decreases an organism&amp;rsquo;s responsiveness to the stimulus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-10</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/links/2021-05-10/</guid>
      <description>Articles
 This Bloomberg article on anti-Asian discrimination in Vancouver The table on the timeline of the Women&amp;rsquo;s Suffrage page on Wikipedia. It&amp;rsquo;s mind-boggling how recently women gained the right to vote. This awesome newsletter entry by Ted Gioia on The Deadliest Song in History. Taking Sex Differences in Personality Seriously  Music
 My Analog Journal. A great YouTube channel that &amp;ldquo;explore rare grooves around the world on vinyl&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of hour long sets, filmed looking straight down at the turntable while he spins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truisms (1978-1983)</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/holzer-truisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/holzer-truisms/</guid>
      <description>TRUISMS (1978-1983) by JENNY HOLZER A LITTLE KNOWLEDGE CAN GO A LONG WAY
A LOT OF PROFESSIONALS ARE CRACKPOTS
A MAN CAN&amp;rsquo;T KNOW WHAT IT IS TO BE A MOTHER
A NAME MEANS A LOT JUST BY ITSELF
A POSITIVE ATTITUDE MEANS ALL THE DIFFERENCE IN THE WORLD
A RELAXED MAN IS NOT NECESSARILY A BETTER MAN
A SENSE OF TIMING IS THE MARK OF GENIUS
A SINCERE EFFORT IS ALL YOU CAN ASK</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klara and the Sun</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/klara-and-the-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/klara-and-the-sun/</guid>
      <description>Klara and the sun by Kazuo Ishiguro  If Klara is super intelligent, why doesn&amp;rsquo;t she know basic facts about the sum, solar system, planetary motion, etc? There is clearly some sort of some theology. Is it because the sun is all important to their existence that their creators programmed this strange theology in place of basic science? I realize now after having finished the book what an anthropocentric viewpoint the above comment takes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change git branch (master to main)</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/change-master-to-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/change-master-to-main/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s another thing I&amp;rsquo;ve googled enough times to just put it somewhere I know.
First, rename your local branch:
❯ git branch -m master main Then you can check that it worked:
❯ git status On branch main Your branch is up to date with &amp;#39;origin/master&amp;#39;. nothing to commit, working tree clean If you don&amp;rsquo;t have dependencies that might get screwed up by simply renaming your master branch, you can just navigate to your remote directory and change the name (if you use github, from the repo&amp;rsquo;s home page, click Settings &amp;gt; Branches and then click the edit button that looks like a little pencil).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flask wordcount app</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/simple_flask_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/simple_flask_app/</guid>
      <description>I made a simple flask app that takes a URL as input and returns a table and chart of the most used words on the site.
Built with Flask using a Postgres backend. Uses beautiful soup to scrape and process html from given website. Implements a Redis task queue to handle requests. Uses Angular to poll the back end for completion and to display a word frequency chart using JavaScript and D3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change your file permissions, baby!</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/chmod_codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 08:28:54 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/chmod_codes/</guid>
      <description>Knowing how to set file permissions is very useful (for a much more thorough primer than I provied here, see this article). Unfortunately, while this is very easy to do, it is even easier to forget the codes used to do so. So here&amp;rsquo;s how you do it!
The easiest (shortest) way to change permissions is using octal syntax. Octal syntax goes like this:
chmod &amp;lt;owner&amp;gt;&amp;lt;group&amp;gt;&amp;lt;others&amp;gt; filename Where &amp;lt;owner&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;group&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;others&amp;gt; stand for the octal numeral pertaining to that user or group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move and rename all files in a folder</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/cl_move_and_rename_files/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 12:49:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/cl_move_and_rename_files/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to move and rename a bunch of excel files in a folder. This is one way to do it from the command line, copying into a directory in the parent folder. I did it this way to be able to rm -r old_folder after copying my files to the new folder. You could modify it to rename them in place, but I&amp;rsquo;ve accidentally rm -rfed enough things to get nervous doing it that way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello!
My name is Colin. I share my notes, thoughts and a record of my digital wanderings here. I hope you can find something of interest amongst the many things that grab my attention. If you do, I would love to hear from you. You can send me an email at colinspear@gmail.com or find me on Twitter at @colinspear.
By training, I am an economist, a baker, a sculptor and a student of the Spanish language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Count files by type and directory</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/count-files-by-type-and-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/technical-posts/count-files-by-type-and-directory/</guid>
      <description>Using the command line to count stuff</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/borges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/borges/</guid>
      <description>From Funes, the memories:
 These things he told me; neither then nor later have I ever placed them in doubt. In those days there were no cinemas or phonographs; nevertheless, it is odd and even incredible that no one ever performed an experiment with Funes. The truth is that we live out our lives putting off all that can be put off; perhaps we all know deep down that we are immortal and that sooner or later all men will do and know all things.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
