<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Colin Spear</title>
    <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 20:23:04 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/stoicism-vs-sentimentalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 20:23:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/stoicism-vs-sentimentalism/</guid>
      <description>Stoicism vs Sentimentalism Use Agnes Callard&amp;rsquo;s On Anger as an argument against rationality. In this view the truly rational thing is to hold a grudge and exact revenge forever and ever, amen. It is the irrational dissolution of anger that allows for peace and resolution</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-19</title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-19/</guid>
      <description>What are the implications of trying to remain anonymous while trying to be part of the new creator economy?
 There is a new kind of creator economy that is quickly expanding and morphing and dividing and being discussed. Some folks that come to mind that are either creating or speaking about this that come to mind are Nadia Eghbal, David Perell, Anna Gat, Alex Danco, Liminal Warmth, critter I am thinking of some twitter accounts I follow The importance of reputation (Nadia Eghbal and David Perell talk a bit about this on his podcast) and the way production cadences interact with this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/performance-ambivalence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 20:41:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/performance-ambivalence/</guid>
      <description># Craft or crap? The tension between striving and embracing who we are Links  Nietsche vs Kierkegaard Tim Ferris and Brene Brown  When I was much younger, after dropping out of high school in a THC-drenched haze, I spent a lot of time meditating and reading about meditation and buddhist flavored self improvement. I loved it and took it seriously, had a regular practice, attended a regular group meditation, went on retreat and diligently studied the modern western buddhist canon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/people/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 19:28:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/people/quotes/</guid>
      <description>Quotes Devon Zuegel on the North Star Podcast:
 Everything is interesting of you build a mental model for it
 Agnes Callard on the Ezra Klein Show, minute 40:
 I think we&amp;rsquo;re way too quick to identify ourselves with the long term goals, especially when we are not in the moment of being tempted. So we can say, look I know how I should really live. I know that I should really read those books, and I should not not eat the cookies and I should be less stressed about these things; I should spend more time with my family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/learning/cost-of-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 17:48:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/learning/cost-of-housing/</guid>
      <description>Booming real estate prices  Why are prices going up all across the country / continent? How is Vancouver both typical and atypical in this dynamic?  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/learning/tools-for-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 17:48:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/learning/tools-for-thought/</guid>
      <description>Learning  building mental models of everything information theory + Claude Shannon money  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-18</title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-18/</guid>
      <description>Books:
Money: The True Story of a Made Up Thing by Jacob Goldstein. By one of the hosts of Planet Money. Short and interesting, made me want to learn more about the Chinese intellectual and scientific advances from around 600 AD to 1200 AD.
Articles:
 Acceptance Parenting by Agnes Callard Why are non-alcoholic drinks so expensive? Vancouver is the anti-asian hate crime capital of the world. It&amp;rsquo;s also nearly 30% asian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/learning/addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 10:34:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/learning/addiction/</guid>
      <description>addiction Questions  What is addiction? Is it measures by our actions? Our desires? What sorts of things are addictive? What are the consequences of addiction? Who gets addicted? Do we all have addictions to something? What do we do about addiction? How do we engage and interact with it both within ourselves and in our families, communities, countries and the world  Resources  Never Enough by Judith Grisel  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/learning/learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 04:32:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/learning/learning/</guid>
      <description> I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to figure out how to organize the Learning section of the website. Please let me know if you have any ideas or suggestions!
 Things I want to learn more about  Addiction Vocation and work Computer science and programming Tools for thought and how to learn better The cost of housing. Why does it seem to be going up everywhere?  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-11</title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-11/</guid>
      <description>Associative and non-associative learning From the MIT Open Course Introduction to Psychology
 There are two types of learning: associative learning and non-associative learning. Associative learning is when you learn something new about a new kind of stimulus (that is, an extra stimulus). Non-associative learning is when you&amp;rsquo;re not pairing a stimulus with a behavior. Non-associative learning can be either habituation or sensitization.
Habituation is when repeated exposure to a stimulus decreases an organism&amp;rsquo;s responsiveness to the stimulus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-10</title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-10/</guid>
      <description>David Perell&amp;rsquo;s podcast North Star Podcast An interview podcast of a certain set of tech or tech adjacent writers / public intellectual types that is familiar to anyone plugged into that scene on Twitter. Perell is a recipient of the Emergent Ventures Fellowship from the Mercatus Center (of Tyler Cowen fame) and seems to be on a mission to interview just about every Twitter famous tech (adjacent) star out there. I listened to his interview with Michael Nielsen, a Y Combinator research fellow focusing on how we learn and how to learn better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Focus</title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/focus/</guid>
      <description>Focus To what extent can we manufacture focus (asking for a friend :tongue_in_cheek_emoji:)
Canonical answers:
 Develop habits (if you get used to doing the same thing every day out will get easier to do the same thing every day) Organize your physical environment to minimize distraction and promote concentration Minimize your ambition set (i.e. Don&amp;rsquo;t have to many goals) Take care of your mental and physical needs (sleep, exercise, etc)  My strategy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My comparative advantage (the craft of being nice 🤮🤢)</title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/my-comparative-advantage-the-craft-of-being-nice-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/my-comparative-advantage-the-craft-of-being-nice-/</guid>
      <description>My comparative advantage (the craft of being nice :face_with_open_mouth_vomiting::nauseated_face:) It&amp;rsquo;s not often you see your CFO holding back tears. It&amp;rsquo;s even rarer when the reason he&amp;rsquo;s doing so is because you&amp;rsquo;re being fired.
No, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t part of a mass layoff or a restructuring or a merger or anything like that. I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t very good at my job. We all knew it and I had already been interviewing at other places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-03</title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/2021-05-03/</guid>
      <description>What to write?
What I have been reading / listening to:
 Robert Buchholz - Western Civilization 2 Noah Smith - Why Politically Guided Science is Bad Judith Grisel - Never Enough Ted Gioia - Music: A Subversive History Philosophize this podcast: episodes on Locke and Hobbes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas</title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/ideas/</guid>
      <description>Ideas  Persistence. How I&amp;rsquo;m bad at it and how important it seems to be. Persistence vs. novelty or curiosity. The way that doing small things over a long time accumulate Rationality and science vs. Narrative and feeling What is my comparative advantage? **The insularity of the tech world **(the brouhaha around Basecamp, a company of less than 60 people that was the only thing that people talked about in tech for a week) a podcast that interviews high performers on the sacrifices they&amp;rsquo;ve had to make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/randomization-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 21:32:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/randomization-inference/</guid>
      <description>References
 Section in Causal Inference, the mixtape Abadie, Athey paper  Randomization inference Just want to think a bit about what I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about randomization inference
It is an alternative, experiment inspired framework for thinking about and performing causal inference
 Cunningham treats it mostly like a robustness test (from what I can tell) outside of limited contexts, and still maybe in the most appropriate contexts as it&amp;rsquo;s not super mainstream for example, they say that it&amp;rsquo;s especially useful for situations in which, instead of working with a random sample of a population, there is good reason to believe you are working with the entire population itself what does this mean for external validity?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello!
My name is Colin. This is my playground. I share my writing, my notes and my intellectual wanderings here. I hope you can find something of interest amongst the many things that grab my attention. If you do, I would love to hear from you. You can send me an email at colinspear@gmail.com or find me on Twitter at @colinspear.
Purpose of this website:
 To be my digital home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/documents/holzer-truisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/documents/holzer-truisms/</guid>
      <description>TRUISMS (1978-1983) JENNY HOLZER
A LITTLE KNOWLEDGE CAN GO A LONG WAY
A LOT OF PROFESSIONALS ARE CRACKPOTS
A MAN CAN&amp;rsquo;T KNOW WHAT IT IS TO BE A MOTHER
A NAME MEANS A LOT JUST BY ITSELF
A POSITIVE ATTITUDE MEANS ALL THE DIFFERENCE IN THE WORLD
A RELAXED MAN IS NOT NECESSARILY A BETTER MAN
A SENSE OF TIMING IS THE MARK OF GENIUS
A SINCERE EFFORT IS ALL YOU CAN ASK</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/learning/causal-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/learning/causal-inference/</guid>
      <description>Causal inference  Causal Inference: The Mixtape  Similar to Mostly Harmless Econometrics, perhaps a bit more accessible plus a chapter on DAGs   The Effect  I&amp;rsquo;m mostly interested in reading Part I on Research Design   Cyrus Samii course  Recommended by Sean Taylor via Twitter    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/learning/cs-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/learning/cs-programming/</guid>
      <description>Learn Python the right way</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/people/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cactus-fork.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/people/people/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to figure out how to organize the People section of the website. If you have any ideas or suggestions about how to organize a heterogeneous set of complex, indivisible, objects (i.e. humans), please let me know!
 Weirdos and iconoclasts  Quentin Crisp Gwern  A freelance writer and tech guy. Super original and hard to describe briefly.   Dan Reeder  A musician who moved from California to Nuremberg and builds most of the instruments he uses, including recording equipment (computers, amplifiers, microphones and PAs).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
