<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//www.colinspear.com/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Where I&#39;m Calling From, Raymond Carver</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/where-im-calling-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/where-im-calling-from/</guid>
      <description>Frank Martin uncrosses his arms and takes a puff on the cigar. He lets the smoke carry out of his mouth. Then he raises his chin toward the hills and says, &amp;ldquo;Jack London used to have a big place on the other side of this valley. Right over there, behind that green hill you&amp;rsquo;re looking at. But alchohol killed him. Let that be a lesson. He was a better man than any of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sea of Tranquility</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/sea-of-tranquility/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/sea-of-tranquility/</guid>
      <description>Why did Gaspery-Jacques get sent to Ohio where he happened to run into Mirella? It wasn&amp;rsquo;t his decision, was it? Why would the Time Institute want to do that? Was it an accident? It seems too unlikely to be an accident&amp;hellip;
 I think, as a species, we have a desire to believe that we’re living at the climax of the story. It’s a kind of narcissism. We want to believe that we’re uniquely important, that we’re living at the end of history, that now, after all these millennia of false alarms, now is finally the worst that it’s ever been, that finally we have reached the end of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 Books</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/2022-book-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/2022-book-list/</guid>
      <description>Finished  Recursion, Blake Crouch ⭐⭐⭐ Story of our life, Ted Chiang ⭐⭐⭐ Five Little Indians, Michelle Good ⭐⭐ Never Let Me Go, Kazuo Ishiguro ⭐⭐⭐⭐ Exit West, Mohsin Hamid ⭐⭐⭐⭐⭐ The English Patient, Michael Ondaatje ⭐⭐⭐⭐ The Anomaly, Herve Le Tellier ⭐⭐⭐⭐⭐ American Gods, Neil Gaiman ⭐⭐⭐ Sea of Tranquility, Emily St. John Mandel ⭐⭐⭐⭐  Unfinished &amp;gt;50% complete  The Inconvenient Indian, Thomas King ⭐⭐⭐ Shutdown, Adam Tooze ⭐⭐  &amp;lt;50% complete  Crashed, Adam Tooze Neuromancer, William Gibson Split Tooth, Tanya Tagaq  Check out The following are from this Hacker News thread:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exit West, Mohsin Hamid</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/exit-west/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/exit-west/</guid>
      <description>A quote highlighted by Colleen:
 By the time he entered university, Saeed’s parents prayed more often than they had when he was younger, maybe because they had lost a great many loved ones by that age, or maybe because the transient natures of their own lives were gradually becoming less hidden from them, or maybe because they worried for their son in a country that seemed to worship money above all, no matter how much other forms of worship were given lip service, or maybe simply because their personal relationships with prayer had deepened and become more meaningful over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Ending Fire, Wendell Berry</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/world-ending-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/world-ending-fire/</guid>
      <description>This book really pits two of my beliefs against one another. On the one hand, I believe the value of specific, physical places and our relationships with them is vastly underrated. It provides meaning, connects us to the past and encourages a deep respect for people and places that is a necessary counterweight to the obvious trends of the ephemeral, impersonal nature of our modern digitized lives. It is the place from which all efforts at conservation should begin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The English Patient</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/english-patient/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/english-patient/</guid>
      <description>7% : The winds of the world known by the patient. It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely passage. The Wikipedia page on the winds of the world is not nearly as beautiful, but also very cool.
30% : The sapper. The man who defused the landmines left behind by the retreating German military. Kip.
42% : Their distance gives them a private energy. Was this the inspiration for the Helado Negro album?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ted Chiang: Story of our life</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/story-of-our-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/story-of-our-life/</guid>
      <description>Contains spoilers
This was a great novella. A slow burner, it drops its core themes quickly and densely about three quarters of the way through. Language, time, free-will, purpose, parenting are all front and center in this very human human-alien encounter. I love stories that focus on that slippery line between what we have the ability to change and what we don&amp;rsquo;t and how we make sense of this partial self-determination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orwell - Essays</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/orwell-essays/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/orwell-essays/</guid>
      <description>Essays by George Orwell So much of his worldview seems to be about his experience of violence and the political context in which he experienced it.
The scale and scope of violence that was part of European life in the first half of the 20th century is so hard to fathom. Reading Orwell really drives home the idea that this experience was such a formative part of not just political, financial and public life, but the way in which people forged their beliefs and their sense of self - who they were in the world and the ways in which they understood themselves and their role in society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journals, magazines and other online aggregations</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/journal-magazine-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/journal-magazine-list/</guid>
      <description> Works in Progress The Public Domain Review Gapminder (Dollarstreet) Our World in Data Cochrane Library - summaries of state of knowledge based on RCTs  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mind at Play: How Claude Shannon Invented the Information Age</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/a-mind-at-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/a-mind-at-play/</guid>
      <description>A Mind at Play: How Claude Shannon Invented the Information Age by Jimmy Sony &amp;amp; Rob Goodman Information is divorced from content. This was one of the fundamental insights leading up to Shannon&amp;rsquo;s work. Information is not about what you send, it&amp;rsquo;s simply about what you can send, or the set of things you can send. This is kind of amazing to me: developing the technologies that have given us so many platforms for expressing our weirdness and individuality was only possible by ignoring all of that stuff in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conjectures and Refutations</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/conjectures-refutations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/conjectures-refutations/</guid>
      <description>Conjectures and Refutations by Karl Popper  Contrasts the Empiricists (the philosophers that saw truth as something stemming from natural observation) with the rationalists (those that believed truth is something to be found through intellectual intuition) His argument is that both of these camps are not really that different at all. They both believe truth to be something whole that can be obtained in full in one way or the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leondardo da Vinci</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/da-vinci-isaacson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/da-vinci-isaacson/</guid>
      <description>Leonardo da Vinci by Walter Isaacson Introduction  That followed Leonardo&amp;rsquo;s injunction to begin any investigation by going to the source: he who can go to the fountain does not go to the water jar.
 Themes  Iteration and going deeper. The revisiting if the painting&amp;rsquo;s neck twenty years after the initial painting to correctly render the two sternocleidomastoid muscles after human dissection in 1510. Beginning from foundations. First you must paint the skeleton, then move outward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tristes Tropiques</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/triste-tropique/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/triste-tropique/</guid>
      <description>Tristes Tropiques&amp;rsquo; by Claude Levi-Strauss  Mankind has opted for monoculture
 From early in the book, perhaps from the introduction. I don&amp;rsquo;t recall precisely.
Chapter 9   The ground that his observations cover is truly remarkable. In chapter 9, Guanabara, he goes from travelogue to France&amp;rsquo;s early colonial history in Brazil to urban design over the course of only a few paragraphs.
  He speaks of the way that places have ceased to shock and surprise in the way they once did before the sustained contact between colonial and native cultures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truisms (1978-1983)</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/holzer-truisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/holzer-truisms/</guid>
      <description>TRUISMS (1978-1983) by JENNY HOLZER A LITTLE KNOWLEDGE CAN GO A LONG WAY
A LOT OF PROFESSIONALS ARE CRACKPOTS
A MAN CAN&amp;rsquo;T KNOW WHAT IT IS TO BE A MOTHER
A NAME MEANS A LOT JUST BY ITSELF
A POSITIVE ATTITUDE MEANS ALL THE DIFFERENCE IN THE WORLD
A RELAXED MAN IS NOT NECESSARILY A BETTER MAN
A SENSE OF TIMING IS THE MARK OF GENIUS
A SINCERE EFFORT IS ALL YOU CAN ASK</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klara and the Sun</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/klara-and-the-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/klara-and-the-sun/</guid>
      <description>Klara and the sun by Kazuo Ishiguro  If Klara is super intelligent, why doesn&amp;rsquo;t she know basic facts about the sum, solar system, planetary motion, etc? There is clearly some sort of some theology. Is it because the sun is all important to their existence that their creators programmed this strange theology in place of basic science? I realize now after having finished the book what an anthropocentric viewpoint the above comment takes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/borges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/borges/</guid>
      <description>From Funes, the memories:
 These things he told me; neither then nor later have I ever placed them in doubt. In those days there were no cinemas or phonographs; nevertheless, it is odd and even incredible that no one ever performed an experiment with Funes. The truth is that we live out our lives putting off all that can be put off; perhaps we all know deep down that we are immortal and that sooner or later all men will do and know all things.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
