<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>covid on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>https://www.colinspear.com/tags/covid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in covid on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.colinspear.com/tags/covid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-14</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-14/</guid>
      <description>Happy V-day, lovers.
Podcasts  Season Two, Episode Two of What had happened was has a gem of a section that could easily be turned into a 5,000 word think piece on art, ephemerality and the responsibility we have (or don&amp;rsquo;t) when it comes to preserving art that may just fade into nonexistence under current legal and economic conditions. It&amp;rsquo;s this section where I realized that El-P is seeing the whole chessboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-07</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2022-02-07/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts  Open Mike Eagle&amp;rsquo;s What had happened was is a gift to humanity. It&amp;rsquo;s the history of weirdo, independent hip hop from the horse&amp;rsquo;s mouth. Season One with Prince Paul (producer for De la Soul, Stetsasonic, MF Doom, Paul Barman, etc. etc.) was easily one of my favorite podcasts of 2020. I&amp;rsquo;m late to the Season 2 party with El-P (Company Flow, Run the Jewels, etc.), but it&amp;rsquo;s sounding good so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021-06-22</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/links/2021-06-22/</guid>
      <description>2021-06-22 Articles   This article on Patrick Collison, Tyler Cowen and Patrick Jay&amp;rsquo;s reflections on the Fast Grants program they started to fund COVID related research during the pandemic. This quote stands out:
 Scientists are in the paradoxical position of being deemed the very best people to fund in order to make important discoveries but not so trustworthy that they should be able to decide what work would actually make the most sense!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
