<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Doing the work &gt; Preparing for the work</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/performance-ambivalence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/performance-ambivalence/</guid>
      <description>Links  Tyler Cowen and David Perell Anna Gat Music: A Subversive History Agnes Callard on the Ezra Klein Show Me, being oh so witty  Motivating questions  How do we know when to push and when to rest, both at the micro level (e.g. in daily/weekly subproject level) and at the macro level (e.g. what projects to take on, when to quit a project)? What is the relationship between striving and acceptance?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testy testy</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/hypothesis-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/hypothesis-testing/</guid>
      <description>Hypothesize everything Links / Sources / inspirations  Karl Popper&amp;rsquo;s idea that the scientific method is about Conjectures and Refutations. We make a conjecture, then we gather evidence to test the conjecture.  Motivating questions  What is progress? Truth? How do we evaluate our lives? How do we understand our decisions, make sense of our past and make better decisions going forward?  Outline The formal hypothesis test Do a plain language overview, include some charts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it immoral to be rich?</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/morality-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/morality-wealth/</guid>
      <description>Motivation The idea was something I was exposed to and sort of absorbed growing up. I remember having a conversation with some friends who clearly held this view. We were talking about Bill Gates and they seemed to be convinced that he was an evil person which just didn&amp;rsquo;t square with my ideas about the economic, intellectual and technological advances from home computing (not to mention the philanthropy of the Gates Foundation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoicism vs Sentimentalism</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/stoicism-sentimentalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/stoicism-sentimentalism/</guid>
      <description>Stoicism vs Sentimentalism Use Agnes Callard&amp;rsquo;s On Anger as an argument against rationality. In this view the truly rational thing is to hold a grudge and exact revenge forever and ever, amen. It is the irrational dissolution of anger that allows for peace and resolution
Not exactly support for my gotta be irrational to be ethical thesis, but rather the opposite. Anyway, relevant. https://twitter.com/womenpostingws/status/1398786339785433092?s=19</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
