<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book-notes on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book-notes on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conjectures and Refutations</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/popper-conjectures-and-refutations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/popper-conjectures-and-refutations/</guid>
      <description>Popper - Conjectures and Refutations  Contrasts the Empiricists (the philosophers that saw truth as something stemming from natural observation) with the rationalists (those that believed truth is something to be found through intellectual intuition) His argument is that both of these camps are not really that different at all. They both believe truth to be something whole that can be obtained in full in one way or the other. &amp;ldquo;It is plain, just look at these facts!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tristes Tropiques</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/levi-claude-strauss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/levi-claude-strauss/</guid>
      <description>Levi Claude Strauss Mankind has opted for monoculture</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook: The Inside Story</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/facebook/</guid>
      <description>Facebook Interesting that there is such a focus on the importance of and focus on privacy during the birth of the company. Is this propoganda, really how it was, or some combination?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truisms (1978-1983</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/holzer-truisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/holzer-truisms/</guid>
      <description>TRUISMS (1978-1983) JENNY HOLZER
A LITTLE KNOWLEDGE CAN GO A LONG WAY
A LOT OF PROFESSIONALS ARE CRACKPOTS
A MAN CAN&amp;rsquo;T KNOW WHAT IT IS TO BE A MOTHER
A NAME MEANS A LOT JUST BY ITSELF
A POSITIVE ATTITUDE MEANS ALL THE DIFFERENCE IN THE WORLD
A RELAXED MAN IS NOT NECESSARILY A BETTER MAN
A SENSE OF TIMING IS THE MARK OF GENIUS
A SINCERE EFFORT IS ALL YOU CAN ASK</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music: A Subversive History</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/music-a-subversive-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/music-a-subversive-history/</guid>
      <description>Krause describes a memorable encounter with an elder of the Nez Perce tribe named Angus Wilson, who chided him one day: “You white people know nothing about music. But I’ll teach you something about it if you want.” The next morning, Krause found himself led to the bank of a stream in northeastern Oregon, where he was motioned to sit quietly on the ground. After a chilly wait, a breeze picked up, and suddenly his surroundings were filled with the sound of a pipe organ chord—a remarkable occurrence, since no instrument was in sight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klara and the Sun</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/klara-and-the-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/klara-and-the-sun/</guid>
      <description>Klara and the sun  If Klara is super intelligent, why doesn&amp;rsquo;t she know basic facts about the sum, solar system, planetary motion, etc? There is clearly some sort of some theology. Is it because the sun is all important to their existence that their creators programmed this strange theology in place of basic science? I realize now after having finished the book what an anthropocentric viewpoint the above comment takes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/a-mind-at-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/book-notes/a-mind-at-play/</guid>
      <description>A Mind at Play Information is divorced from content. This was one of the fundamental insights leading up to Shannon&amp;rsquo;s work. Information is not about what you send, it&amp;rsquo;s simply about what you can send, or the set of things you can send. This is kind of amazing to me: developing the technologies that have given us so many platforms for expressing our weirdness and individuality was only possible by ignoring all of that stuff in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
