<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>fiction on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>//www.colinspear.com/tags/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fiction on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//www.colinspear.com/tags/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Where I&#39;m Calling From, Raymond Carver</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/where-im-calling-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/where-im-calling-from/</guid>
      <description>Frank Martin uncrosses his arms and takes a puff on the cigar. He lets the smoke carry out of his mouth. Then he raises his chin toward the hills and says, &amp;ldquo;Jack London used to have a big place on the other side of this valley. Right over there, behind that green hill you&amp;rsquo;re looking at. But alchohol killed him. Let that be a lesson. He was a better man than any of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sea of Tranquility</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/sea-of-tranquility/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/sea-of-tranquility/</guid>
      <description>Why did Gaspery-Jacques get sent to Ohio where he happened to run into Mirella? It wasn&amp;rsquo;t his decision, was it? Why would the Time Institute want to do that? Was it an accident? It seems too unlikely to be an accident&amp;hellip;
 I think, as a species, we have a desire to believe that we’re living at the climax of the story. It’s a kind of narcissism. We want to believe that we’re uniquely important, that we’re living at the end of history, that now, after all these millennia of false alarms, now is finally the worst that it’s ever been, that finally we have reached the end of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klara and the Sun</title>
      <link>//www.colinspear.com/books/klara-and-the-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.colinspear.com/books/klara-and-the-sun/</guid>
      <description>Klara and the sun by Kazuo Ishiguro  If Klara is super intelligent, why doesn&amp;rsquo;t she know basic facts about the sum, solar system, planetary motion, etc? There is clearly some sort of some theology. Is it because the sun is all important to their existence that their creators programmed this strange theology in place of basic science? I realize now after having finished the book what an anthropocentric viewpoint the above comment takes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
