<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>drafts on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/tags/drafts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in drafts on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/tags/drafts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Taking biproject slowdown seriously</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/slow-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/slow-projects/</guid>
      <description>Taking big project slowdown seriously Links
 https://www.motherjones.com/kevin-drum/2012/07/why-does-it-take-so-long-build-stuff-these-days/ https://reason.com/2021/03/25/why-does-american-infrastructure-cost-more-and-take-longer-to-build-than-it-used-to/  An evaluation of one (or more) of Patrick Collison&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Fast&amp;rdquo; projects compared to something similar today
Why might big projects take longer now than in the past?
  Regulation both good and bad
 health and safety environment    other
 more alternatives available now than in the past (even if the alternatives aren&amp;rsquo;t that great)    I feel like there&amp;rsquo;s been a major formalizing of economic, social and political life over the last century that is somehow related to this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it immoral to be rich?</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/morality-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/morality-wealth/</guid>
      <description>Motivation The idea was something I was exposed to and sort of absorbed growing up. I remember having a conversation with some friends who clearly held this view. We were talking about Bill Gates and they seemed to be convinced that he was an evil person which just didn&amp;rsquo;t square with my ideas about the economic, intellectual and technological advances from home computing (not to mention the philanthropy of the Gates Foundation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The value of activities with low economic return</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/divergent-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/divergent-returns/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by an exchange between Rob Henderson and David Perell about the importance of &amp;ldquo;being able to get rich&amp;rdquo; as an incentive to draw overeducated people into the internet content production machine1 economy.
Links  unbuilders The cost of running a restaurant  Motivating questions  What are some high value add activities / businesses / sectors where economic returns don&amp;rsquo;t seem to match social benefits? Where is the economic return to business far lower than the social benefit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoicism vs Sentimentalism</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/stoicism-sentimentalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/posts/stoicism-sentimentalism/</guid>
      <description>Stoicism vs Sentimentalism Use Agnes Callard&amp;rsquo;s On Anger as an argument against rationality. In this view the truly rational thing is to hold a grudge and exact revenge forever and ever, amen. It is the irrational dissolution of anger that allows for peace and resolution
Not exactly support for my gotta be irrational to be ethical thesis, but rather the opposite. Anyway, relevant. https://twitter.com/womenpostingws/status/1398786339785433092?s=19</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
