<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>quotes on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>https://www.colinspear.com/tags/quotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in quotes on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.colinspear.com/tags/quotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/people/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/people/quotes/</guid>
      <description>Quotes Devon Zuegel on the North Star Podcast:
 Everything is interesting of you build a mental model for it
 Agnes Callard on the Ezra Klein Show, minute 40:
 I think we&amp;rsquo;re way too quick to identify ourselves with the long term goals, especially when we are not in the moment of being tempted. So we can say, look I know how I should really live. I know that I should really read those books, and I should not not eat the cookies and I should be less stressed about these things; I should spend more time with my family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music: A Subversive History</title>
      <link>https://www.colinspear.com/book-notes/music-subversive-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.colinspear.com/book-notes/music-subversive-history/</guid>
      <description>Krause describes a memorable encounter with an elder of the Nez Perce tribe named Angus Wilson, who chided him one day: “You white people know nothing about music. But I’ll teach you something about it if you want.” The next morning, Krause found himself led to the bank of a stream in northeastern Oregon, where he was motioned to sit quietly on the ground. After a chilly wait, a breeze picked up, and suddenly his surroundings were filled with the sound of a pipe organ chord—a remarkable occurrence, since no instrument was in sight.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
