<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Colin Spear</title>
    <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Colin Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Colin Spear</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Physical vs digital innovation</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/physical-vs-digital-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/physical-vs-digital-innovation/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the difference between innovation and technology that manipulated the physical world versus that which is primarily digital.
Questions
 Is there some sort of natural cap on the returns to digital technologies? Will more software, including most AI really impact our lives and the economy in world changing ways? Software may be eating the world, but what are the limits on how much it can change the world?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agglomeration economies and the internet</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/agglomeration-economy-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/agglomeration-economy-internet/</guid>
      <description>Agglomeration economies and the internet Links
 https://ideas.repec.org/a/eee/juecon/v73y2013i1p94-110.html  Motivating questions
 What is the effect of the internet on agglomeration economies? How much of the benefits of colocation are ameliorated by the internet? What are the contours of the Internet&amp;rsquo;s effect on the benefits of colocation? Obviously, being in the same place is still important. In what ways can the internet allow people to capture these benefits and in what ways is it still limited?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confusion</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/confusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/confusion/</guid>
      <description>Confusion I am working through a task at work of reproducing a dataset using a long SQL script consisting of separate chunks of data manipulation and manual edits (to the data table, not the code). As often happens, documentation is less than perfect and I am left to figure out much of what I am doing in my own. This naturally leads to some confusion - what should I be looking for, how do I find an issue to correct, how should I correct the issue when I find it etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics of anonymity in the creator economy</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/anonymity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/anonymity/</guid>
      <description>What are the implications of trying to remain anonymous while trying to be part of the new creator economy?
 There is a new kind of creator economy that is quickly expanding and morphing and dividing and being discussed. Some folks that come to mind that are either creating or speaking about this that come to mind are Nadia Eghbal, David Perell, Anna Gat, Alex Danco, Liminal Warmth, critter I am thinking of some twitter accounts I follow The importance of reputation (Nadia Eghbal and David Perell talk a bit about this on his podcast) and the way production cadences interact with this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/focus/</guid>
      <description>Focus To what extent can we manufacture focus (asking for a friend :tongue_in_cheek_emoji:)
Canonical answers:
 Develop habits (if you get used to doing the same thing every day out will get easier to do the same thing every day) Organize your physical environment to minimize distraction and promote concentration Minimize your ambition set (i.e. Don&amp;rsquo;t have to many goals) Take care of your mental and physical needs (sleep, exercise, etc)  My strategy:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associative and non-associative learning</title>
      <link>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/associative-non-associative/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>main.d1zllkef03p41t.amplifyapp.com/notes/associative-non-associative/</guid>
      <description>Associative and non-associative learning From the MIT Open Course Introduction to Psychology
 There are two types of learning: associative learning and non-associative learning. Associative learning is when you learn something new about a new kind of stimulus (that is, an extra stimulus). Non-associative learning is when you&amp;rsquo;re not pairing a stimulus with a behavior. Non-associative learning can be either habituation or sensitization.
Habituation is when repeated exposure to a stimulus decreases an organism&amp;rsquo;s responsiveness to the stimulus.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
